https://www.vinography.com/privacy-policy

Vinography a wine blog
Toggle navigation
Wine ReviewsRed WineWhite WinePink WineOrange WinesSparkling WineDessert WinePerfect 10sWines under $20Undiscovered WinesOlder VintagesBoutique WinesWine Not To BuySakeBook ReviewsImagesRamblings and RantsMessages In A BottleThe Essence of WineI’ll Drink to ThatWine NewsEventsWine ActivitiesFood ActivitiesAbout
follow:
search
Privacy PolicyThis is the privacy policy for Vinography and it was last updated on May 4, 2020. If you have questions or concerns, please contact us.Who we areWe are a wine blog and informational web site that includes wine reviews, news, editorial opinions, photography, and more. Our website address is: https://www.vinography.com.What personal data we collect and why we collect itWe collect personal data on only three occasions:your e-mail address when you subscribe to our weekly newsletteryour name, e-mail and any data included in your comments when you choose to comment on an articlethe form data collected as part of the Contact Us form.CommentsThe comment system is run by Disqus, which means any personal information you enter in order to or as part of a comment is housed in their system. They offer privacy controls as part of their interface. You may always choose to comment as a guest, without registration of any kind.When visitors leave comments on the site or use the Contact Us form, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help with spam detection and for analytics purposes. See Analytics below for more information.CookiesIf you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies run by the Disqus service. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.If you visit home page, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.First-time visitors to the web site will also have a cookie set in their browser once they have accepted the GDPR-related cookie disclaimer on the site, as well as one used to prevent you from being bothered by repeated suggestions to subscribe to our newsletter. These cookies will last until deleted.We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work, the following social media sites including Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, and Reddit will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.Google Ads also utilizes cookies. Please see Advertising below.Embedded content from other websitesArticles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.AdvertisingWe serve ads from Google’s Adsense network on this site. If you have questions or concerns about the ads on this site, please see Google’s Advertising Principles which exist to ensure you have a good experience.We have implemented the following:Google Display Network Impression ReportingDemographics and Interests ReportingGoogle uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART and DoubleClickcookies enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Google utilizes cookies to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.AnalyticsThis site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google Analytics page.Who we share your data withAny data directly collected by Vinography is never, ever shared with any third party. We have never, and will never sell our list of subscriber e-mails or names to any third party for any reason. As noted above, third parties such as Google Adsense and Google Analytics will collect anonymized / aggregate user data about your activities on this site.How long we retain your dataIf you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.What rights you have over your dataIf you have left comments on this site, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.Where we send your dataVisitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service and are logged through our comment functionality provider, Disqus.Your contact informationFor users who send their contact information as part of a form submission for a newsletter subscription or a contact request, this data is retained indefinitely to allow for communications between us and you. Newsletter opt-out and do-not-contact options are available via our marketing automation service, iContact, and appear at the bottom of every e-mail newsletter.How we protect your dataWe make every commercially reasonable effort to protect the very limited amount of data that this site collects. We use best-in-class network hosting and security providers and access to these environments is restricted to one or two people only.What third parties we receive data fromWe receive data from the third party providers noted above, namely Disqus, Google and iContact. With the exception of comments on articles and newsletter subscription information, all data received from third parties is aggregated and anonymized, and used to understand the performance of this web site, its content and functionality.Share this:FacebookTwitterPinterestRedditFollow on Instagram:
When Riesling is good it has this weightlessness t
Evil Twin II
Evil twin.
Not a black and white photo. Just an autumn day in
If you had to pick a wine that somehow managed to
Yes, this is how I nap. Got a problem with that?!?
That Swiss nose, though.
I’m gonna eat this, mmkay?
My Book The Essence of Wine. A visually stunning wine book like no other. 2015 Roederer Award Winner. Learn moreSubscribe Via Email Receive weekly notifications of new posts.
Free Tasting ToolUse Vinography’s free aroma card to help you learn how to better identify the flavors and aromas in wine. In seven languages! Learn more. Useful LinksMy Delectable FeedMy Vivino FeedThe Wine Lover’s Essential LibraryThe Complete List of Wine BlogsVinography’s Flipboard MagazineVinography RSS FeedRestaurant Review ArchivesContact Us© 2004–2020 Vinography: a Wine Blog by Alder Yarrow is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution- NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.Permissions beyond the scope of this license may be available by request. Please contact us for more information. Read our Privacy Policy.
Join our NewsletterWould you like to receive weekly updates of new postings to vinography.com? Enter your e-mail below. Only one e-mail per week, and we’ll never sell your details to anyone.
No thanksWe use cookies on this site to give you the best experience. This includes features such as remembering your desired language preference, not bugging you with repeated suggestions to sign up for our e-mail summaries, etc. If you continue to use the site we assume you accept these cookies and the way we are using them. Read our privacy policy. OK
Close GDPR Cookie Settings
Privacy Overview
Strictly Necessary Cookies Powered by  GDPR Cookie Compliance Privacy OverviewThis website uses cookies so that we can provide you with the best user experience possible. Cookie information is stored in your browser and performs functions such as recognising you when you return to our website and helping our team to understand which sections of the website you find most interesting and useful. Strictly Necessary CookiesStrictly Necessary Cookie should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for cookie settings.
Enable or Disable Cookies
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that every time you visit this website you will need to enable or disable cookies again. Enable All Save Settings
